

Averkamplaan 8, 3533SL Utrecht, The Netherlands

□+31 (0)6 17 857 720 | ■ me@robertwinters.nl | ★ https://robertwinters.nl | the wintersrd

# Summary\_

A hands-on manager with 12 years experience in building and leading analytics teams. Demonstrated capacity for hiring and growing a team, setting direction and vision, and achieving results through others. A practicing data scientist and BI engineer, fluent in all aspects of technical implementation within a data environment. Experienced in using data to identify opportunities and drive outcomes across disciplines including Marketing, Customer Service, and Sales, and in industries including Telco, Gaming, Retail, and Travel.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**TravelBird BV** Amsterdam, The Netherlands

HEAD OF DATA SCIENCE 2015-Present

- · Hired to launch green-field initiative to build a data stack, data science team, and introduce BI to organization
- A member of the company Management Team, responsible for company decision making on topics including strategy, budget, and staff
- Led the design and implementation of end-to-end omni-channel personalization platform, improving CTR 15% and content viewed 34%
- Designed and led the roll out of a full BI/data science tech stack built on AWS and open source technologies and developed a training program to support **500%+ data growth** and an organization of 650+ end users
- · Led the design and implementation of an improved marketing attribution model, reducing spend 60% for a 8% reduction in revenue
- · Hired and led a multi-disciplinary team of data scientists, BI engineers, and developers, receiving employee engagement scores in the 91nd percentile globally

de Bijenkorf Amsterdam, The Netherlands

**HEAD OF DATA TECHNOLOGY** 2014-2015

- · Hired to lead a green-field initiative to set up a new BI/analytics technology stack to replace traditional legacy system
- Implemented a fully cloud-based BI architecture which was highly performant, fault tolerant, and 90% lower cost than the existing solution
- · Designed and developed a fully automated, metadata-driven Data Vault architecture to integrate data from more than a dozen systems
- · Redesigned the event tracking architecture to improve accuracy by better than 40% and reduce event delay from 24 hours to seconds
- · Hired in foundational team members to extend the technology stack and drive utilization in the organization

**Spil Games** Hilversum, The Netherlands

DIRECTOR, REPORTING AND ANALYTICS

2011-2014

2006-2011

- · Hired to introduce analytics, data warehousing, personalization, and data driven decision making into the organization
- · Built a cross-functional team of engineers, analysts, and data scientists to set up data technology stack and create meaningful analysis from the data
- Implemented a BI solution that achieved >60% daily company usage via the creation of more than 120 reports from 80+ different sources
- · Created the personalization platform and models to personalize 40 websites and deliver 10 million predictions and 50 million recommen-
- Created segmentation and demographic prediction models to provide improved advertising targeting information for 80% of gameplays
- Implemented content recommendation and optimization models, improving email efficiency by 46% and on-portal engagement by 11%

**T-Mobile USA** Bellevue, WA, USA

• Finance lead for six-month, \$323M cost reduction exercise reporting to the CEO

- In partnership with SVP, created a cross-sell program to drive \$156M a year in revenue by:
  - Evaluating customer and contact opportunities to create offers and programs. Led to a 118% lift in data sales and 52% lift in insurance sales
  - Set targets, bonuses, and forecast plans to drive operational performance
  - Created product survival models and margin analysis to optimize product mix
- · Defined and managed a financial portfolio of automation initiatives reducing costs \$17M annually
- Restructured Customer Service bonus plan to drive \$15M annual reduction in handle time

## Education

SENIOR MANAGER, ANALYTICS

#### **Western Governor's University**

Salt Lake City, UT, USA

MASTER'S OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION - IT MANAGEMENT

2014-2016

- · Comprehensive MBA program with additional focus on IT strategy, data driven decision making, and project management
- Graduation project consisted of assessment of a local company and identification of critical areas for technology improvement in Finance, IT, and Product

AUGUST 19, 2018 ROBERT D WINTERS · RÉSUMÉ **Open University**Milton Keynes, UK

POSTGRADUATE STUDIES - PHILOSOPHY

Completed coursework with merit

### **Western Washington University**

Bellingham, WA, USA

B.A. ECONOMICS / INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

2001-2005

2012-2014

 Active volunteer with a number of organizations including Big Brothers Big Sisters, Boys and Girls Club, and Outdoors for All (outdoor activities for the disabled)

#### **Assorted**

CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAININGS COMPLETED

- Deep Learning Coursera.org
- Certified Professional Scrum Master Scrum.org
- Prince2 Project Management

## Skills\_

**BI Tools** Tableau, Airflow, Pentaho

**Databases** Vertica, Postgres, Redis, MySQL, Teradata, Oracle 11

**Analytical Tooling** Keras, Spark, Tensorflow, R, Jupyterhub

**Programming** AWS, Python, Bash, Git

Algorithms ALS, Random Forest, Neural Nets, Classical Regressions, Clustering